Elliot Arnold papers, 1920s-1980, (bulk, 1934-1980).
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Elliot Arnold papers, 1920s-1980, (bulk, 1934-1980)
MS 387
Elliott Arnold,; Jean Arnold Sessler
Collection includes biographical materials, correspondence, manuscripts, short stories, and articles written by Elliott Arnold. The collection also contains research files, newspaper clippings and photographs.
25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical Note
Elliott Arnold was born September 13, 1912, in New York City to parents Jack and Gertrude Frank Arnold. He attended college at CCNY and NYU. He began his writing career while in college, as a reporter at the Brooklyn Times. He wrote his first novel Two Loves at 18 years old. In 1932 he started writing for the NY World Telegram. During his time there he wrote Personal Combat, Only the Young, Finlandia, and The Commandos. Soon after the attack on Pearl Harbor he enlisted in the army and was assigned to the Army Air Corps. He helped in the collaboration of two official air histories, Mediterranean Sweep and Big Business. After four years in the military he was awarded the Bronze Star Metal by General MacArthur and was discharged with the rank of captain.
Elliott Arnold then went on to be a prolific writer of novels, short stories, and articles. His novels include; Blood Brothers, Time of the Gringo, Flight from Ashiya, A Night of Watching, The Proving Ground, and the Camp Grant Massacre. Many of his short stories and articles have appeared in Playboy, Reader's Digest, and Colliers. A number of his works went on to become screen plays. In 1950 Broken Arrow, based on his novel Blood Brothers was released by Twentieth Century-Fox, and in 1964, A Flight from Ashiya was released by United Artists.
During his lifetime Arnold had been acknowledged for numerous awards including: the Commonwealth Club of California Silver Medals in 1948, for Blood Brother, in 1960, for Flight from Ashiya, and in 1968, for A Night of Watching, and the Screen Writers Guild prize for Broken Arrow, in 1951. Elliott Arnold died May 13, 1980, in New York City.
Organization
This collection is organized into eight series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1935-1978
Series 2: Correspondence, 1934-1981
Series 3: Manuscripts, ca.1934-1976
Series 4: Articles, 1931-1979
Series 5: Research Files, ca.1817-1979
Series 6: Clippings and Promotional Material, ca.1939-1980s
Series 7: Photogaraphs Awards, and Drawings, 1930s-1979
Series 8: Manuscripts by Other Authors, 1970s-ca.1978
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes biographical materials, correspondence, manuscripts, short stories, and articles written by Elliott Arnold. The collection also contains research files, newspaper clippings and photographs. The majority of the collection consists of original manuscripts, short stories and articles written by Elliott Arnold.
The bulk of the correspondence contains letters received in the 1960s and 1970s from agents, business associates and friends which document Elliott Arnold's publishing activities at the time. The Photographs include mostly black and white photos of Elliott Arnold during his military career, publicity shots throughout his lifetime, and autographed photographs of individuals, including Jimmy Stewart. Most of the collection is arranged alphabetically within each series.
Access Terms
Arnold, Elliott, 1912- --Archives.
Carney, Otis -- Manuscripts.
Mitchell, Burroughs -- Manuscripts.
Winston, Irene -- Manuscripts.
United States. Army -- History.
Short stories, American -- 20th century.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Aerial operations, American -- History.
American fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism.
Militarism in literature.
West (U.S.) -- In literature.
Container List
- Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1935-1978
  - Scrapbook, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Squadron Book, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Data on Elliott Arnold, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appointment Book, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Appointment Book, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Appointment Book, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Appointment Book, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Appointment Book, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appointment Calendar, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Appointment Book, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appointment Book, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Appointment Book, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Appointment Book, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Appointment Book, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Appointment Book, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Appointment Book, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Appointment Book, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Appointment Book, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Appointment Book, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Appointment Book, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Appointment Book, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Appointment Book (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1934-1981
  - A-B, 1934-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - C-D, 1950-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Elephant Bill, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - E-L, 1946-1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - M-S, 1945-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - T-Z, 1942-1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Unknown 1950-1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series 3: Manuscripts, ca. 1934-1976
  - Alverez, Kelly, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alverez, Kelly, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Arsenal (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bandoola 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Blood Brothers (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Blood Brothers (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Bloodied Years (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Bloodied Years (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Bloodied Years (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Bloodied Years (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Bloodied Years (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Bloodied Years (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Bloodied Years (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bonanza, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brave Jimmy Stone 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Broken Arrow, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Broken Arrow (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Camp Grant Massacre 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Camp Grant Massacre, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Camp Grant Massacre, uncorrected proofs, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Camp Grant Massacre (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Camp Grant Massacre (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Code of Conduct, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Code of Conduct (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Code of Conduct (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cowards to the Rear-Brave Hearts Follow Me, First Draft (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cowards to the Rear-Brave Hearts Follow Me, First Draft (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cowards to the Rear-Brave Hearts Follow Me, Second Draft (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cowards to the Rear-Brave Hearts Follow Me, Second Draft (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cowards to the Rear-Brave Hearts Follow Me, Second Draft (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cowards to the Rear-Brave Hearts Follow Me, Third Draft (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cowards to the Rear-Brave Hearts Follow Me (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Everybody Slept Here, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fiesta in the Desert/Nine Shots in the Dark (not by Elliott Arnold) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Flight From Ashiya, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Flight From Ashiya, October 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Flight From Ashiya, December 1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Flight From Ashiya, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Flight From Ashiya, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Flight From Ashiya, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Day Custer Fell, Preliminary Notes, 1962? (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Day Custer Fell, Treatment, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Day Custer Fell, Screenplay, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Decision, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Deep in My Heart, Biography of Sigmund Romberg, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Deep in My Heart, Biography of Sigmund Romberg, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Door (pg.1-223) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Door (pg.224-432) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Door (1-216), Edited (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Door (217-432), Edited (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Elephant Bill, Original Copy, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Elephant Bill, First Draft (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Elephant Bill, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Elephant Bill, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Elephant Bill, First Screenplay, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Forests of the Night (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Forests of the Night (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Forests of the Night (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Forests of the Night (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fort Buchanan, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Kimberly, treatment, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - A Kind of Secret Weapon, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Kings of the Sun, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Man Who Found His Way (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Mound Builders, August 1962 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Mound Builders, November 1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Mound Builders (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Navy Story, by Frank Harvey, August 1962 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Navy Story, by Frank Harvey, November 1962 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Navy Story, by Elliott Arnold, August, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - A Night of Watching, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - A Night of Watching, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - A Night of Watching (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Opera- an outline for a film (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Penthouse East- episode one teleplay (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Place Where the Devils Dwell (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - The Place Where the Devils Dwell (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Place Where the Devils Dwell (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Place Where the Devils Dwell (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Place Where the Devils Dwell (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The Place Where the Devils Dwell (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Place Where the Devils Dwell (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - A Proving Ground, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - A Proving Ground (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Quicksand, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Quicksand (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Quicksand (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Quicksand, Pg.A-200 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Quicksand, Pg.201-400 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Quicksand, Pg.401-553 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Rawhide, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Rawhide, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Rescue (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Rescue, July 27, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Rescue, July 6, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Richmond Story, December 1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Shields of Africa - Magic Box (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Shields of Africa - Man Eater (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Shields of Africa - The Slaves (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The Spirit of Cochise (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Stagecoach Station (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Two Loves, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Partial Manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Partial Manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Untitled Screenplay (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Untitled Novel (pg. 1-133) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Untitled Novel (pg. 134-286) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Untitled Novel (pg. 287-413) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Walk with the Devil, a three act play (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Walk with the Devil, a three act play (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Walk with the Devil, a three act play (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - The Year of the Dragon (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Short Stories: 7 O'clock News (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Short Stories: An Act of Grace (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Short Stories: Alter Ego (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Short Stories: An Awakening Minority- The American Indians (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Short Stories: Assistance Please... (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Short Stories: A Bay Chance (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Short Stories: A Brief Smile (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Short Stories: Buck Larkin and a Girl Named Henry (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Short Stories: Come and Let Us Dream (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Short Stories: The Dawn Breakers (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Short Stories: The Days of the Week (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Short Stories: Dead on Arrival (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Short Stories: During Winter Wind (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Short Stories: The Door (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Short Stories: Early to Bed (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Short Stories: A Feeble Complaint- An Observation (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Short Stories: The Frailty of the Potables (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Short Stories: A Free Theatre (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Short Stories: From the Dark (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Short Stories: A Helpful Man from San Berdoo (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Short Stories: I am Afraid to Sleep (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Short Stories: I Got to Stay Up! (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Short Stories: In Flight (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Short Stories: Israel: Two Quarter Time (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Short Stories: It Happened in Monterey (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Short Stories: Jamie (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Short Stories: The Legend of the Blue Lady (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Short Stories: The Little Elephant Who Always Forgot (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Short Stories: The Little Mermaid (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Short Stories: A Manhattan Dream (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Short Stories: The Masquerade (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Short Stories: Me and Tom Wolfe (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Short Stories: A New Kind of Suspense and Adventure (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Short Stories: Night Crossing (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Short Stories: Not Without Reward (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Short Stories: Old Marty (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Short Stories: One American's Involvement with Scandinavia (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Short Stories: Pick (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Short Stories: Please Don't Feed the Animals (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Short Stories: Portrait of An Artist as a Young Man (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Short Stories: Rafferty: the Rat (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Short Stories: The Return (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Short Stories: ROD (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Short Stories: Safe House (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Short Stories: Should I Put on Some Makeup (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Short Stories: Spring Time (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Short Stories: Still a Little Time (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Short Stories: Short Stories: Summer Scene Change (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Short Stories: A Sunday in Westchester (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Short Stories: The Sweet Smell of Grass (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Short Stories: That Certain October… in 1943 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Short Stories: Thirty Cents (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Short Stories: To Be a Hero (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Short Stories: To Escape (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Short Stories: Trial Heat (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Short Stories: The Wallflower (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Short Stories: We Are Such Things... (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Short Stories: What Did I Do That Was Wrong (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Short Stories: Where are they Now (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Short Stories: You Never Can Tell, Can You? (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Short Stories: Untitled (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Series 4: Articles, 1931-1979
  - Broadway; Imaginary Interviews - No. 4 Harry Richman, February 7, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Broadway; Imaginary Interviews - No. 5 Buddy Rogers, February 21, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - (publication unknown) New York Sketches, December 19, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Boston Record: On Broadway, August 1932 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn Daily Times, 1932-1934 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Cue: Heartbreak on the Air, August 15, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Nation: The Used Car Racket, September 19, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Nation: Letters to the Editor November 7, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Nation: Faking Automobile Accidents, November 21, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The Nation: The Ambulance Chasing Game, November 28, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Cue: Operatic Overture, December 12, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - New York World Telegraph: Action in Precinct 27, 1936-1940 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Cue: Going, Going Gone!, January 9, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Cue: Let Us Vibrate, February 20, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - The American Scandinavian: Sibelius is Finland, February 1941 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Omnibook: The Commandos, August 1942 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Periodicals- Miscellaneous (Arnold not mentioned), 1958-1973 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - The Saturday Evening Post: Where's That Bomber, October 7, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Omnibook: Tomorrow Will Sing, April 1945 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Friends: Colorful Arizona is Setting for Historical Film - Broken Arrow, August 1950 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - The Tucson Magazine: Elliott Arnold, March 1951 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Tucson Festival of the Arts: Tucson, March - April 1951 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Collier's: That Others May Live, July 6, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Harper's Magazine: Secret Mission to Rome, October 1944 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Liberty: Tomorrow Will Sing, June 9, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Liberty: Everybody Slept Here, November 1948 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Movie Story: Broken Arrow, July 1950 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Hadassah Magazine: A Night of Rescue, October 1968 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Sarie Marais: The Accident, July 1969 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Playboy: Night Crossing, November 1970 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Playboy: What Did I Do That Was Wrong, October 1972 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Scanorama: The American Indian, May 1973 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Playboy, Italian Edition: Ma Che Spaglio ho Fatto?, July 1973 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Playgirl: The Anatomy of a Live Sex Show, February 1974 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Scanorama: The Frailty of Potables, April - May 1974 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Scanorama: Eating out in Manhattan, August - September 1977 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Playboy: A Bay Change, June 1979 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Scanorama: Remembering Sibelius, August - September 1979 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Story: Portrait of Allison (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Series 5: Research Files, 1817-1979
  - Airplane Hijacking, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - The Apache Past and Present, Vol.1, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - The Apache Past and Present, Vol. 2, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Army, Senate Files (Pt.1), ca. 1870s (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Army, Senate Files (Pt.2) ca. 1870s (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Camp Grant Massacre- Correspondence, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Camp Grant Massacre - Camp Grant Correspondence (Includes Photograph), 1874 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Camp Grant Massacre (Pt.1), 1871-1971 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Camp Grant Massacre (Pt.2), 1871-1971, no date (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Crime - Clippings, 1976, no date (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - The Door 1967-1986 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Pueblo Incident, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Raoul Wallenberg (Includes Correspondence) (Pt.1), 1961-1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Raoul Wallenberg (Pt.2), 1961-1979 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Red Cloud (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Adjutant General of the Army, Correspondence (Pt.1), 1817-1888 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Adjutant General of the Army, Correspondence (Pt.2), 1817-1888 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Series 6: Clippings and promotional Material, 1939-1980's
  - Clippings: Blood Brother/Broken Arrow, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: The Camp Grant Massacre (Pt.1), 1976 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: The Camp Grant Massacre (Pt.2), 1976 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Clippings: Code of Conduct, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: Code of Conduct (Pt.1), 1970 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Clippings: Code of Conduct (Pt.2), 1970 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Clippings: Code of Conduct, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Commandos, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: Everybody Slept Here, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: Elliott Arnold, 1942-1980 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Clippings: Flight from Ashiya, 1959-1964 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Clippings: Forests of the Night (Pt.1), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Clippings: Forests of the Night (Pt.2), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Clippings: Scrapbooks, 1939-1955 (Box 13)
  - Clippings: General, 1940-1949 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: General, 1950-1959 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: General, 1960-1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: General, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: General (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Clippings: A Night of Watching, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Clippings: A Night of Watching (Includes Correspondence), 1967-1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Clippings: Mediterranean Sweep, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Nose for News, 1942-1945 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: Only the Young, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: Personal Combat, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: Proving Ground (Pt.1), 1973 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Clippings: Proving Ground (Pt.2), 1973 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Clippings: Quicksand, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Clippings: The Rescue, 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Time of the Gringo, 1953-1955 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: Tomorrow Will Sing, 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Clippings: White Falcon, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Promotional Material: Code of Conduct, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Promotional Material: A Night of Watching, 1967-1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Promotional Material: Miscellaneous, ca. 1960s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Series 7: Photographs, Awards, and Drawings, 1930's-1979
  - Photographs: Blood Brothers/Broken Arrow (Includes Autographs of Broken Arrow Cast Members), ca. 1947-1956 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Broken Arrow Television Show, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Elliott Arnold (Includes Negatives) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Elliott Arnold, Family, and Friends (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Elliott Arnold - Military - General (Includes Negatives), 1930s-1940s (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Elliott Arnold - Military - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Elliott Arnold - Military - Research, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: Elliott Arnold with Unidentified People, ca. 1940-1970s (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Military - New Guinea, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Military - Regensburg Germany, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous - Buildings (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous - Grade School, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: Musicians (Autographed Photos), 1939 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: Publicity Photographs and Proofs (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Photographs: Unidentified People (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Awards: Certificates, 1950-1979 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Awards: Plaques (Box 16)
  - Oversize Photographs, Drawings, and Awards (Box 17)
- Series 8: Manuscripts by Other Authors, ca. 1970s
  - Archer, Kak- Seekers, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Arnold, Tom - The Resistant Strain, no date (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Black Elk Productions - The First Americans, 1970s (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Boxer, Lester - The Sabbatical, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Carney, Otis - Nothing Lives Long, Only the Earth and the Mountains, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell, Burrows - Education of an Editor (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Winston, Irene - The Donnybrook Fighter, no date (Box 18, Folder 7)